LAUREN CIULLA VISUAL DESIGNER

NYC-based designer combining experience in visual, multimedia, and UX design with a passion for creativity and getting teams to thrive. Dedicated to leading with design and helping clients express themselves and their ideas through digital content.

CONTACT

lauren.m.ciulla@gmail.com

lauren-ciulla.com

Inkedin.com/in/lauren-ciulla

(203) 260 - 2013

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT 2016 - 2020 BA / / DIGITAL MEDIA & DESIGN

Graduated summa cum laude from Honors Program.

Earned a concentration in Web & Interactive Media.

Published Honors Thesis titled "User Research and Real User Problems: Improving the User Experience of Online Shopping."

BA / / ENGLISH

Graduated summa cum laude.

UNIVERSITY OF RICHMOND Jan 2019

Winter course: Rome, Italy.

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER Jul 2017

Summer course: London, UK.

HONORS & AWARDS

IBM CIO Design Hero Award 2022 IBM Advanced Digital Video Content Designer Badge 2022 New England Scholar Award 2020 Aetna Undergraduate Writing in the Disciplines Honorable Mention 2020 IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator Badge 2019

TOOLS & SKILLS

Babbidge Scholar Award

Adobe Creative Suite / / Figma / / Procreate Cinema4D / / RedShift / / OBS Storyboarding / / Event production Content design // User research Enterprise Design Thinking / / Agile

2018 & 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

VISUAL DESIGNER / / IBM

Aug 2020 - Present

Produce live events hosted by IBM executives for global audiences averaging 3,000 people, opening a line of communication for the CIO.

Lead visual design effort on an internal pricing and costing tool, incorporating UX designs, stakeholder interests, and IBM's Carbon Design System.

Create 2D and 3D animated videos, which includes conceptualizing vision, facilitating stakeholder ideation, performing content design, storyboarding, and illustrating assets.

Conduct user research, IBM Enterprise Design Thinking activities, and user testing throughout the design process to pinpoint user needs and ensure user-centered design.

Mentor junior designers in visual/multimedia design & navigating the design landscape.

CIO DESIGN INTERN / / IBM

May 2019 - Aug 2020

Developed research-based content, UX, and visual design for a resource to help designers work effectively in Agile and a website to guide interns through onboarding.

Created graphics and videos for display on IBM social channels and in office spaces.

DESIGN INTERN / / Greenhouse Studios

Nov 2017 - Jan 2020

Designed/developed solutions for VR work, immersive web narratives, and a Vue.js app.

SENIOR EMAIL MARKETING INTERN // UConn Foundation Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

Formulated digital engagement strategies encompassing timelines and content for multichannel engagement (email, social, web) to promote sporting/recreational events.

Executed email campaigns by designing emails, A/B testing variable content to maximize performance, and synthesizing email reports into user-friendly recommendations.

DIGITAL GRAPHIC ARTIST/DEVELOPER / / UConn Comms. Dec 2018 - Feb 2019 Implemented original graphics, illustrations, and JavaScript code to improve the UI/UX of an educational video game.

FREELANCE DESIGNER MARKETING INTERN / / HPOne

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 May 2018 - Aug 2018

Designed and coded animated HTML5 banner ads featured in Google AdWords slots.

Created Medicare-focused infographics with original content, graphics, and illustrations for content marketing material.

Organized, advertised, and executed events to promote engagement and recruitment.

INVOLVEMENT & LEADERSHIP

DESIGNOPS SUMMIT COHORT FACILITATOR / / Rosenfeld Media

Deepened DesignOps Summit participants' understanding of conference material by organizing activities and facilitating discussions.

PANEL SPEAKER / / Design at IBM

Jul 2022

Sep 2022

Shared experience and advice on the design landscape inside and outside IBM.

PODCAST PANELIST / / Digital Media CT

Jun 2020

Discussed careers in design and Design Thinking on "Beyond the Tech/IBM" episode.

DESIGN THINKING WORKSHOP FACILITATOR / / Girls Who Code Aug 2019

Facilitated Design Thinking activities promoting rapid ideation and Agile methodologies.